Guide to the Street Hall, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Street Hall, Yale University, photographs
1864-1911
RU 698
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The materials consist photographs and pictures of Street Hall at Yale (formerly known as the Art Building). Included are views of construction, studios, galleries, and classrooms.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist photographs and pictures of Street Hall at Yale (formerly known as the Art Building). Included are views of construction, studios, galleries, and classrooms.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs, Series I
  - Construction, 1864-1866 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General views
    - 1866-1894 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 7)
    - Post-1895 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Interior views
    - Study galleries, pre-1878 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - J. F. Weir's studio, pre-1878 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Main Gallery, pre-1878 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Entrance hall, pre-1878 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Jarves Gallery, pre-1878 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Main Gallery, post-1887 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Jarves Gallery, post-1887 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Second floor stairwell, post-1887 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Lecture Hall -Alden carvings, post-1887 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Library, post-1887 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous, post-1887 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Sculpture Gallery, pre-1900 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Sculpture Gallery, [post-1900?] (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Main Gallery, [post-1900?] (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Galleries, [post-1900?] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Architect's drawings (prints of)
    - Front perspective, Circa 1863 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Front elevation, Circa 1863 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Longitudinal section, Circa 1863 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Proposed tower, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Addition, floor plans, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Oversize, 1:20 Street Hall (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Slides, (art students working) (Box 4)
  - Folio
    - From Chapel with Pierson Statue (Box DR23F75)
    - From Chapel without Pierson Statue (Box DR23F75)
    - Interior (Box DR23F75)
    - Entrance hall and stair (Box DR23F75)
    - South Gallery (Box DR23F75)
    - Gallery (Box DR23F75)